CHRIS CHATEAU SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Employment

Peerfit. Junior Web Client Engineer

Remote, 2019 to 2020

- Worked primarily with React, Redux, React Router and SASS
- Added extensive integration and end-to-end testing using Cypress
- Tracked engagement analytics and implemented A/B tests
- Hired as full employee after 8 months in a full time contract role

Self-Employed, Equity Trader

Denver. CO. 2016 to 2018

Tower Hill Trading, Equity Trader

Chicago, IL, 2014 to 2016

Mayan Families, Website & Database Coordinator Guatemala, 2013 to 2014

About Me

I am a passionate, detail oriented programmer who takes pride in everything I do. I lived abroad for a year managing website and database duties for a non-profit organization in Central America. This position gave me my first taste of giving back through my work and doing something positive for others. My years as a trader sharpened my skills as a researcher, but left me missing the opportunity to collaborate with others and build meaningful projects. In addition to my love of coding, I am drawn to software development for the opportunity to work with a team in order to build something that will have a positive impact on people's lives.

Projects

Long Shot League

A bold twist on March Madness, the Long Shot League is a selfdirected, three phase project built using React, ExpressJS, Knex and PostgreSQL.

Summit Register

Summit Register is my capstone project from The Turing School of Software & Design, completed in collaboration with three other students. The front-end was written with React and fully tested with Jest & Enzyme.

Marvelous

Using React, React Router and Redux; Marvelous allows users of all ages to explore the Marvel Universe one character at a time. Marvelous was a solo project completed in one week while at the Turing School of Software & Design and fully tested with Jest & Enzyme.

christopherchateau@gmail.com

chrischateau.com 5173043407

in christopherchateau

christopherchateau

Education

Turing School of Software and Design 2018 to 2019

Front-End Engineering Program

Michigan State University

2000 to 2005

Bachelor of Arts Psychology

Skills

JavaScript

React JS

Redux

JOuery

HTML5

CSS3

SASS

Object Oriented Programming

Cypress

Mocha/Chai

Jest/Enzyme

Git/Github

Responsive Design

Continuous Integration

Heroku

REST API

Express JS

PostgreSQL

NPM / YARN